

ABOUT MYSELF

Hey there I'm Jakob and I Love working in the field of software development and am currently open to more Work in 2024. I enjoy working with Next.js or React.js, Typescript and Tailwind however I've learnt many languages and am open to all. I employ advanced object oriented principles and skills in my work and projects and have extensive experience with mentoring, team development and interpersonal skills.

I love martial arts and if I'm not at the computer I'm outdoors, enjoying the beach or training.

I've recently been upskilling myself and working on some development through courses on Udemy and working with Liquid, python and Node. I am excited to grow in this industry and I'm constantly investing my free time into new languages, frameworks and improving my skills. Feel free to message or checkout my portfolio to learn more and get in contact.

CONTACT

PHONE:

0433351248

EMAIL:

Jakobdouglas1@gmail.com

LINKEDIN:

www.linkedin.com/in/jakob-douglas

PORTFOLIO:

www.iakobdoualas.dev

Jakob Douglas

TECHNICAL SKILLS (INCLUSIVE BUT NOT LIMITED TO)

Preferred Programming Languages

JavaScript/TypeScript/ Python/ SQL

Front-End

Next.js, React.js, JQuery, Tailwind, Axios, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Sass/SCSS, Redux.js

Back-end

Node.js, Express.js

Databases & ORMs

MongoDB, Postgres, Mongoose, MySQL

Build/Tooling

Webpack, Vite, ESLint, Babel

Testing

Jest, Supatest

DevOps

Git, Github, Vercel, Netlify, Render

SaaS Platforms

SendGrid, Supabase, OpenStreetMaps

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Advanced Computer Science(Honors) Griffith University

2024-present

Bachelor of Health science (Masters in Physiotherapy) Flinders University

2018 - Present

HOBBIES

Martial arts (have represented SA nationally and trained overseas)

Health and Fitness

Travel and acquiring new skills

Mixology

Programming and Coding

REFEREES

Available on request

RELEVANT WORK AND PROJECTS

GITHUB

https://www.aithub.com/iakolandio3

Portfolio SitePortfolio Site

Dec 2023 - Jan 2024

-My 2024 Portfolio site, built with Next.js and Tailwind using popular packages such as Sendgrid and DaisyUI. Check it out at https://www.jakobdouglas.dev

The Wild Oasis

Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

-Application for booking cabins designed for staff usage with authentication and back end hosted with Supabase, FullStack- real world application that is fast, fully interactive and client friendly https://the-wild-oasis-seven-khaki.vercel.app/

World-Wise

Oct 2023 - Nov 2023

-SPA made with Vite + React that tracks where you have traveled featuring a responsive design and open source map from Leaflet https://world-wise-snowy.vercel.app/

TS-React-Redux-RFC-Template

2024

React-Redux template Functional Component version (with TS + Tailwind + DaisyUI). Built for framework and learning purposes. https://github.com/jakolandio3/TS-React-Redux-RFC-Template

Web-Framework 2024 (Typescript)

2024

A custom build web framework to use for building applications with, consisting of compilers for Typescript.

https://github.com/jakolandio3/Back-End-WebFramework-Typescript_is-2024-/tree/feat/class-view

TS-Express-Routing

2024

a small routing project using TypeScript and Express for learning and practicing

https://github.com/jakolandio3/TS-Express-Routing/tree/refactor/v2-using-adapter-library

FURTHER SELF-EDUCATION

Shopify Theme Development: Online Store 2.0 + TailwindCSS 2024

- -How to set up your development store
- -Using TailwindCSS to design a Shopify theme
- -Online Store 2.0 (JSON Templates)
- -Shopify CLI

- -Schema Settings
- -Search Engine Optimization (SEO) for pages like articles, products, etc.
- -Liquid language (Referencing asset files, loops, conditional statements, Shopify objects, filters, and many more)
- -Customer pages

Typescript: The Complete Developer's Guide 2024

-Typescript masterclass, working with frameworks such as JS, React and packages like Redux to create strict type checking in your dev environment

MERN Stack Front To Back: Full Stack React, Redux & Node.js 2024

- -Build a full stack social network app with React, Redux, Node, Express & MongoDB
- -Create an extensive backend API with Express
- -Use Stateless JWT authentication practices
- -Integrate React with an Express backend in an elegant way
- -React Hooks, Async/Await & modern practices
- -Use Redux for state management
- -Deploy to Heroku with a post-build script

Node is with Test Driven Development

2023

- -Practice Test Driven Development in a real project from beginning to the end
- -Learn the test runner, Jest and understand how to structure test modules
- -Create a fully functional application with Express js
- -Learn how to build a RestFul API
- -Make your application configurable to work in different environments
- -Make your application aware of user locale, and support internationalization, i18n
- -Use Sequelize to connect the application to RDBMS like PostgreSQL and handle all database related operations
- -Secure your application with common practices. Basic authentication, -JWT and your custom token implementation
- -Use javascript on server side with Node is
- -Deploy the application to a VM in cloud
- -Experience automated deployment by pushing a commit from your machine to Github. Github Actions will do the rest.
- -Feel how the test driven development is giving confidence when refactoring, and deploying your application.
- -User Registration with email verification flow, account activation Password Reset flow

The Ultimate React Course 2024: React, Redux & More

2023-2024

- -React, Context API, React Query, Redux Toolkit, Tailwind, advanced patterns
- -Udemy Course

Python Django: Dev to deployment

2023

- -Basic Python (lists, dictionaries, functions, conditionals, etc)
- -Setup Virtual Environments
- -install & configure Django
- -Create Django "apps"
- -Postgres Setup (local and remote)
- -Schema planning, models & migration
- -Admin customization
- -Bootstrap integration
- -Full search functionality
- -User Authentication
- -Deploy to Digital Ocean with Gunicorn & Nginx

Modern JavaScript From The Beginning 2.0 - 2023 Revamp

2023

- -JavaScript, Node, SQL, Back and Front End Development
- -Udemy course

Modern HTML & CSS From The Beginning (Including Sass)

2023

- -HTML5 CSS3 and cass Sass
- -Udemy course

MORE CERTIFICATES

AHTS Training- Cert II in Hospitality

2013

- -Responsible service of alcohol
- -Responsible service of Gaming
- -Health and safety procedures

AHASA- Gaming (Basic certificate)

2017

-Basic gaming, use of machines and laws surrounding them as well as how to write reports and cash handling.

AHASA-Gaming (Advanced Certificate)

2019

-Advanced gaming, dealing with governing bodies and refresher of previous course

Certificate IV in Personal Training and Ffitness

2022-2023

AHASA- Gaming (Further Advance Gaming)

2020 - Present

-Gaming Management and refresher course

WORK EXPERIENCE

BarRiot-Bartender/Service Staff

- -2022-2023
- -Creating cocktail lists
- -Expanding wine knowledge and providing my knowledge to guests
- -Full knowledge of dining options so that I can explain the dishes thoroughly to guests including background on origins etc.
- -Optimising team processes through shifts
- -Delegation of work for optimal efficiency in real time
- -Tills and functions systems (explaining systems to new staff along with contacting techs for software improvements and updates)

2KW- Bar and Function team

- -2022
- -Cocktail bar work on the terrace
- -General stocktake
- -Dining service
- -Function food and catering services
- -Creating a bespoke environment for functions
- -Liaising with sommelier for wine pairings

Orpheus Island Lodge- Marine Office/ 5-star dining / cocktail classes

- -2021-2022
- -Liaising with guests to organise activities
- -Crowd management and delegation of daily duties
- -Working with smaller teams within a greater community for one overarching goal
- -One on one interaction with guest/s to create a bespoke experience
- -Dining services catered to individuals with 5-star service and exclusive menus
- -Creating and running a variety of "masterclasses" for guests to experience including cocktail classes and wine/spirit tastings
- -Bar service inclusive of stock ordering creating menus stocktake etc.

Highway Hotel – Food and Beverage attendant / Functions supervisor / Gaming Manager

2016-present

- -Organizing and running private functions of up to and over 200pax
- -Liaising with kitchen and BOH to run a timely service of entrée main and desert service
- -Memorizing seated positioning and tables without the need of physical aids
- -Memorizing and reciting large scale orders for tables
- -Providing silver service for functions and dining
- -Knowledge of cocktails and flair for main bars
- -Cash handling up to and over 30K daily
- -Floating tills and balancing back-end systems and safes

- -Till and macros system management
- -Dealing with cheques and EFT transfers
- -Dealing with barring systems police and governing bodies
- -Handling any and all situations in a timely manner while keeping the patron happy
- -Patron evections and mediation
- -External events and functions
- -Service with a smile (Even under a Mask)

The Pontoon on the Torrens - Food and Beverage attendant

2018-2019 (seasonal work)

- -Provide high class casual dining and drinking atmosphere for clients
- -Provide food and beverage service
- -Restrict access to those with passes or admittance
- -General maintenance and cleaning duties
- -Stock management
- -Set up and use mobile till and macros systems
- -Cash and food handling procedures

2KW – Bar Attendant / Boots and maintenance staff

2016-2017

- -Provide a fun and safe environment in this upper-class cocktail bar
- -Set up for the bar including bar and restaurant
- -In charge of stock and Keg rooms
- -Furniture and hotel maintenance
- -Bar service
- -Till operation
- -Working with external events and hotels within the CBD

The International Tourism Hostel in Qufu (CHINA)- Hostel Cocktail and Bar manager

2015-2016

- -Memorizing classic and new cocktails and providing service with flair
- -Till and booking management
- -Cleaning
- -Cash handling
- -Stock ordering
- -Includes working behind the Shangri-la Hotel Bar serving cocktails on a Halloween event
- -Communicating with tourists and locals alike
- -Creating a warm and welcoming environment despite a language barrier
- -Food service both casual and table

TGI Fridays – Bar manager/ Service attendant / Waiter

2013-2015

- -Coffee and Desert preparation and service
- -Table Service
- -Bar management
- -Stock management
- -Rostering and shift changes
- -Creation of Beverage lists including wines and cocktails
- -Cash handling
- -Customer service

- -Booking system management
- -Till system management
- -Suggesting pairings of wines for food
- -Flair bartending
- -Corner Bar Theory

Verve Bar – Bar supervisor

2014-2015

- -Delegate roles within the restraint and bar
- -Provide cocktail beverages both traditional and new
- -Provide table service
- -Till and back of house management and accounting
- -Pay roll duties
- -Cleaning duties
- -Deal with customer requests and or complaints professionally and in a timely manner

Texas Bull Machine- Food and beverage attendant/ Function coordinator and cook (mobile catering)

2009-2017

- -Provide beverage and food service
- -Set up large scale functions Like weddings and military dinners
- -Provide both silver service as table service as well as roaming canapes
- -Run small private functions without need of direction
- -Cook meals and set up spits and banquet tables for up to 200+ patrons
- -Manage cash
- -Manage food safely both cooked and raw
- -Cart service as well as abilities to carry more than 4 plates at a time
- -Customer service at casual and extremely professional levels depending on the event catered to